This is the solutions video for adjust-results4-isadog.
本视频将讲解 adjust_results4_isadog 的解决方案
First, we need to define the adjust-results4-isadog function.
首先 定义函数 adjust_results4_isadog
The doc string indicates that we have the following input parameters, results-dic,
这里的文档字符串指出我们有以下输入参数
the dictionary with the image filename as its key and a list as its value.
字典 results_dic 该字典以图像文件名为键 以列表为值
Where these lists indicate,
字典列表包括
the pet image label,
宠物图像标签
the classifier label, and whether the labels match.
分类器标签以及两种标签的匹配结果
In this function, we'll be adding to this list to indicate if the pet label is a dog,
在这个函数中 我们还要往列表里添加一些内容
and if the classifier label is a dog.
分别说明宠物标签和分类器标签是否为犬类
Dogsfile, a text file that contains
还要输入的参数有文本文件 dogsfile
all the dog names used by both the pet image label and the classifier label.
该文件包含宠物图像标签和分类器标签都会用到的犬名
Finding the label in this file,
能在这个文件中找到的标签
means that label is a dog.
都为犬类标签
This function returns nothing,
函数 adjust_results4_isadog 没有返回值
because the results-dic dictionary is mutable,
因为字典 results_dic 是可变的
and changes that happen to the dictionary within the function,
所以字典在函数内部的变化
are seen outside of the function.
会延续到函数外部
First, we create an empty dictionary dognames-dic.
首先 创建一个空字典 dognames_dic
This dictionary will hold all the dognames in dogsfile.
这个字典会存储 dogsfile 里的所有犬名
Next, we open dogsfile reading one line at a time from the file,
接着 打开 dogsfile
using a while loop until we reach the end of the file.
用 while 循环逐行读完整份文件
We must read in the first line using the read line function,
我们必须先用函数 readline 读取第一行
then we enter the while loop.
再进入 while 循环
In the loop, we strip the new line off the read in dogname using the rstrip function.
在循环里 用函数 rstrip 把跟在读取犬名后的空格删除
Then, if the dogname doesn't already exist in dognames-dic,
如果字典 dognames_dic 尚无某个犬名
we add it to the dictionary.
那我们就将该犬名加入字典
Otherwise, we print a warning that there's a duplicate dogname.
否则 就输出警告 说明已有重复犬名
At the end of the loop,
在循环末尾
we read in the next line using read line.
用函数 readline 读取下一行
We will check at the top of the loop with
另外 我们要在循环开端使用条件语句
a conditional statement if we process this line,
检查是否继续处理下一行
or if we've reached the end of the file.
还是已经到达文件末尾
If the line is empty,
如果下一行是空的
we've reached the end of the file,
那我们就到了文件末尾
and the loop will terminate.
循环由此终止
Next, we iterate through the results-dic dictionary,
接着 对字典 results_dic 进行迭代
extending the value lists by whether or not the labels are dogs.
判断标签是否为犬类 从而扩展列表值
We use nested conditional statements to determine if the labels are dogs,
使用嵌套条件语句来确定标签是否为犬类
then, we use the extended function to append these two items to the end of the list.
若是 则用函数 extend 在列表末端追加两项
The first item appended indicates whether the pet label is a dog,
第一项表明宠物标签是否为犬类
the second item appended indicates whether the classifier label is a dog.
第二项表明分类器标签是否为犬类
If the label is found within dognames-dic,
如果能在 dognames_dic 中找到标签
we know the label is of a dog.
那就证明该标签为犬类
Here in the code,
在这段代码里
we found the pet label is a dog.
我们发现宠物标签为犬类
If the classifier label is a dog,
此时 如果分类器标签也为犬类
we extend by the values 1,1.
那就在列表中追加值 (1 1)
If the classifier label isn't a dog,
如果分类器标签不为犬类
we extend by the values 1,0.
那就在列表中追加值 (1 0)
Here in the code, we found that the pet label isn't a dog.
在这段代码里 我们发现宠物标签不为犬类
If the classifier label is a dog,
此时 如果分类器标签为犬类
we extend by 0,1.
那就追加值 (0 1)
If the classifier label isn't a dog,
如果分类器标签不为犬类
we extend by 1,1.
那就追加值 (0 0)
Now results-dic has been changed to indicate
这样 results_dic 就修改好了
whether the labels are of dogs and the function ends.
可用来表明标签是否为犬类了 函数到此结束
This is the function call to adjust-results4-isadog function within the main function.
这里 我们在主函数里调用了函数 adjust_results4_isadog
This function returns nothing.
该函数没有任何返回内容
Adjust-results4-isadog inputs the arguments result_dic,
adjust_results4_isadog 的输入参数有
the dictionary that was returned by the classify images function,
字典 result_dic 该字典由函数 classifier_images 返回而出
this dictionary has the image file name as its key,
以图像文件名为键
a list as its value,
以列表为值
where the list contains the pet image labels,
其列表值包含宠物图像标签、
the classifier labels, and whether the labels match.
分类器标签和标签匹配结果
When this function completes,
等函数 adjust_results4_isadog 运行完毕
we'll have added to this list to indicate whether the labels are of dogs.
这个字典的列表就会得到追加 从而说明标签是否为犬类
In-arg.dogfile, the command line argument for
函数还有一个参数是 in-arg.dogfile 这是文本文件的命令行参数
the text file that contains all the dognames used
该文本文件包括
by both the pet image labels and the classifier labels.
宠物图像标签和分类器标签都会用到的所有犬名
We'll use this temporary code here to check our code.
我们用这里的临时代码来检查代码
We're going to print all the matches,
依次输出所有匹配结果
followed by all the non matches.
和不匹配结果
We'll visually check whether the labels of dogs have been coded correctly,
观察犬类标签的代码是否正确
and then we'll check if the non-matches
然后检查
added to the matches equals the 40 images we are expecting.
不匹配数加匹配数是否等于 40 也即是否符合实际图像数
Let's go to the terminal window to check our code.
我们来看终端窗口 进行代码检查
At the top, we can see,
可以看到这上面
we call the check images Python program, and below,
调用了程序 check_images.py
we see we have our matches first,
下面先输出了匹配结果
and it seems that the labels are correctly classified as dogs or not dogs.
看来所有犬类和非犬类标签都得到了正确分类
We scroll down, and we see where we have the not a match images,
向下滑动滚轮 我们可以看到不匹配的图像
and they also seem to be classified correctly as dogs or not dogs.
这些犬类或非犬类图像也得到了正确分类
We have a total of 35 matches,
匹配数为 35
five not matches for a total of 40 images as we expect.
不匹配数为 5 加起来就是 40 与实际的图像数目相符
So it seems that our code is working correctly.
可见代码无误